We give thanks for the gift of King T'Challa.
The Black Panther.
Son of King T'Chaka.
My son.
Descendant of the most revered King Bashenga,
the first Black Panther.
We release you.
Praise the ancestors.
France has information that vibranium can be
used to make weapons of mass destruction.
It does not trigger any known metal detector.
It is a threat to global security
and the non-proliferation regime.
I just lost security visuals.
Down on your stomachs right now!
Face to the floor! Go! Go!
Where are the vibranium tools?
Who has access?
Kneel!
You're welcome.
Go!
My Queen.
My Queen,
Yes, my Queen.
Oh my!
Kill the scientist.
I'll deal with the witnesses.
OK.
Kill that woman first.
Go to Namora.
You're not worth my blade.
What's taking so long?
This is not a time for games.
Permission to speak...
my Queen?
I beg of you.
I'm asking you, mother.
Hello.
You're here for the headmistress?
She's there.
Very good.
Hello.
Please excuse us for a moment.
Thank you.
That was a long time ago.
Princess.
Here royalty wears traditional clothing.
We had this made for you.
Come with me.
Eat?
Hello Ma'am. It's nice to meet you.
What can I help you with?
My name is Maria Aldana.
I'm a student from Merida...
I'm not interested. Go away. Please.
Yes, of course. I don't mean to bother you.
Just give me a second...
My professor mentioned a study
where you told researchers that
you encountered something...
Someone unimaginable.
Nothing good came of speaking
with those outsiders.
I'm begging you.
Leave. Now.
I've encountered him too.
Sometimes we would catch a
glimpse of a man with winged feet...
...on the shore of the beach.
We thought he was a spirit.
The K'uk'ulkan.
Our Feathered Serpent God,
...of this realm and the realm below.
I would very much like to visit that beach.
Be warned...
K'uk'ulkan has been here for
much longer than you and I.
Others who have searched for him
with ill in their hearts...
have never returned.
Lost to the depths...
forever...
No. My baby.
Your baby is sick.
Only this can heal him.
Your baby will be the first to be born
in our new home.
Take this gift as a promise...
He will be our new king.
Let's go!
Whose child is this?
Shoot!
FIRE!
Thou art a demon.
Son of Satan.
Thou art a child without love.
The child without love.
You have been summoned...
K'uk'ulkan.
Drop your spear!
Kill the Princess!
Drop your knife.
You...
You killed her.
Let her go
and you don't have to die.
Move your left arm.
You're welcome.
What happened my child?
The Wakandans.
They came for her.
K'uk'ulkan...
can you save me?
Is she dead?
Yes.
Rest child.
They came...
while you spoke to the Queen?
We should not have trusted her.
The Princess has seen our home.
What is stopping them
from coming for Talokan?
I will.
Rise Talokan!
I was blinded
by hope
of partnership.
And...
I have compromised
all of us.
Talokan
will not move
again.
Namora.
Attuma.
When we are done with them
they will never think
of approaching
Talokan!
Rise Talokan!
Take this one.
Let us turn! Turn around!
Take the child.
Warrior!
...my child.
Yes.
We'll find your mama, OK?
The defenses have been lured
away from the palace.
It is up to you now.
Mayday!
Come on, my Queen.
Wake up, my Queen.
Let me see.
Wake up.
Wake up, Mother.
She has passed.
Listen to me.
Hey, Shuri.
You did it!
Ramonda.
We beg of you, come to your daughter.
Are you OK?
What's going on?
Yes.
Are we clear?
Breathe.
K'uk'ulkan, another machine to
detect vibranium is in use in the ocean.
Where?
Get out of the water!
Retreat back!
Sink the ship!
Warrior!
You speak the mother tongue?
You can greet your ancestors with it...
You will greet your ancestors.
I need water.
Imperius Rex.
I yield.
Talokanile'ex!
Let us return home.
Our fight here is done.
What is troubling you, my child?
I looked forward to fighting
alongside you my entire life...
The thought of you
kneeling to the Wakandans...
The Black Panther
had every reason to kill me.
Why do you think
she didn't go through with it?
The Black Panther is the most powerful person
in the most powerful nation on the surface.
But she has no allies.
Now she has empathy
for the people of Talokan.
With this alliance...
Talokan will be stronger than ever.
The surface world will come for Wakanda
and Wakanda will turn to us.
Trust me.
Let's go.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Welcome!
Who are you?